outdooractive.com 2019-09-04

# Data protection at outdooractive.com » outdooractive.com

### § 6 Use of our mobile app.

(1) Information regarding the collection of personal data.

(a) In addition to our online services, we also offer an app that may be downloaded to your mobile device. The following informs you about the collection of personal data when using our website. 'Personal data' is all information that is directly and personally related to you, e.g. name, address, e-mail addresses, user behavior

(b) Liable parties are pursuant to Art. 4 para. 7 of the EU-Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (DS-GVO)

**Outdooractive GmbH**

**Missener Straße 18**

**87509 Immenstadt**

**Phone: +498323-80060**

**E-Mail:[info@outdooractive.com](mailto:info@outdooractive.com) **

**Managing Director: Hartmut Wimmer**    
(see Imprint).

You can reach our data protection officer using the following contact details:

**Anwaltskanzlei Schenk Datenschutz Rechtsanwaltsgesellschaft mbH**

**Auf der Wies 18**

**87727 Babenhausen**

**Phone: 08333-926936-0**

**Telefax: 08333-926936-1**

**E-Mail:[info@europajurist-schenk.com](mailto:info@europajurist-schenk.com) **

**Managing Director: Rechtsanwältin Sabine Schenk.**

 (c) When you contact us by email for via a contact form, the data you have provided (your email address, first and last names, gender and nationality) is saved by us in order to better answer your questions. We delete the data provided in connection with this after its storage is no longer required or, in the case of legal obligations relating to its storage, we limit its use.

(d) Wherever we use contracted service providers to promote our products, or we use your data for advertising purposes, we will inform you as detailed below about the processes involved. We will also notify you of the criteria during the period your data is stored.

(2) Your rights

(a) You have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

–The right to information.

–The right to amendments or deletion.

–The right to restrict use.

–The right to object to use.

–The right to the transfer of data.

(b) You also have the right to lodge a complaint against us for using your data with the Data Protection Supervisory Authority.

(3) Collection of data when using our mobile app

(a) When downloading the mobile app, the required information is transferred to the app store, in particular the username, email address and customer number linked to the account, the time of download, payment information and individual device code. We have no influence on this data collection and are not responsible for it. We process the data only to the extent that is necessary to download the app to your mobile device.

(b) When using the app, we collect the personal data described below in order to facilitate convenient use of the functions. If you choose to use our app, we collect the following data, which is a technical requirement for us to offer you the features of our app and to ensure stability and security (legal basis is art. 6 para. 1 S. 1 lit. f DS-GVO):

–IP address

–Date and time of request.

–Time zone difference in relation to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)

–Request's content (concrete page)

–Access status / http status code

–Volume of data transmitted each time

–Website from which the request originated

–Browser

–Operating system and its interface

–The language and version of the browser's software

–Geodata.

(c) We also require your device's identification, International Mobile Equipment Identity (IMEI) number, International Mobile Subscriber Identity (IMSI), mobile number (MSISDN), Wireless LAN MAC address, the name of your mobile device and e-mail address. In the event that you are a 'Pro' customer, your bank details will also be collected.

(d) In addition to the data listed above, cookies are also saved when using our website. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard drive and assigned to your chosen browser through which certain information flows to the location that sets the cookie (in this case us). Cookies cannot run programs or transmit viruses to your computer. They serve to make the internet more user-friendly and effective.

(aa)The mobile app uses the following types of cookies, the scope and functionality of which are explained below:

–Transient cookies (refer to bb)

–Persistent cookies (refer to cc).

(bb)Transient cookies are automatically deleted once you close the app, including session cookies in particular. They store a so-called session ID, which assigns various requests to your mobile app. This allows your mobile device be recognized when you use it next time. Session cookies are deleted once you log out or close the app.

(cc)Persistent Cookies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which differs depending on the cookie itself. You can configure the settings of your device's operating system and the app to suit your preferences and, for example, decline to accept third party or all cookies. We would like to make you aware that doing this may make you unable to use all of the features of the app.

(e) For advertising purposes we use a so-called 'Advertising Identifier' (IDFA). This is a unique but non-personalized and non-permanent identification number for a particular device provided by iOS. The data collected through the IDFA will not be linked to any other device-related information. The IDFA is used by us to provide you with personalized advertising and to evaluate your use. If you enable 'no ad tracking' in the iOS setting under 'Privacy'-'Advertising', we are only able to take the following actions: Measure your interaction with banners by counting the number of times a banner is displayed without being clicked on ('frequency capping') and evaluate the click- through rate, unique user detection, unique user detection, security measures, fraud prevention and troubleshooting. You can delete the IDFA ('reset Advertising ID') at any time in the device settings, creating then a new IDFA that is not merged with the previously collected data. We would like to make you aware that restricting the use of the IDFA may make you unable to use all of the features of the app.

(f) Collection of your location data

(aa)Our products include so-called Location Based Services, with which we offer specific services that are tailored to your location. You are only able to use these functions after agreeing via a pop-up that we can anonymously collect both your data using GPS and your IP address for the purposes of providing a service. You can permit or disable this function within the settings of the app or your operating system at any point by calling up the settings in (...)

Your location will be regularly relayed to us following your confirmation, at which point we will only use your last recorded location and delete previous notifications relating to your location. When the location survey is active, your smartphone indicates that the data is being processed via a compass icon in the upper bar.

(bb)For the purposes of advertising, market research and demand-oriented design of the offer, we create user profiles using pseudonyms. These data are not combined with other personal data. You can object to this by clicking on the corresponding button in the app settings. You are also welcome to contact [info@outdooractive.com](mailto:info@outdooractive.com) or the address given in the imprint.

(g) When you start using our mobile app, we will request your permission via a pop-up to use your address book, calendar, photos and reminders. If you do not grant us permission, this information will not be used. We would like to make you aware that doing this may make you unable to use all of the features of the app. You can grant or refuse permission subsequently in the app's settings.

(bb)If you permit us access to this data, the mobile app will only access and transfer it to our server for purely functional purposes. Your data will be handled confidentially and deleted if either you remove permission for it to be used or if it is no longer required to render services and/or there is no legal need for it to be stored (legal basis is art. 6 para. 1 P. 1 lit. f DS-GVO)

(4) Dissemination of data to Facebook

(aa)By using our app, your data will be passed on to Facebook. Within Germany and according to Facebook, the IP address is made anonymous immediately after being collected. By activating the app, your personal data will be transmitted to Facebook and stored by them in the US.

(bb) We have no influence on the data that is collected and the mechanisms for processing this data, nor are we aware of the full extent of the data collection, the purpose of its use or the duration it is stored. We have no available information relating to Facebook's data deletion policy.

(cc)Facebook stores the data collected in respect of you as user profiles and uses these for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or the customization of its website's design. Such analysis is carried out in particular (including for users not logged in) in order to display targeted advertising and to inform other users of the social network about your activities on our website. You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles and you must contact Facebook in order to exercise this right (legal basis for the use of Facebook is art. 6 para. 1 S. 1 lit. f DS-GVO).

(dd)Data is transferred irrespective of whether you have a Facebook account or are logged in to one. If you are logged in to Facebook, the data of yours that is being collected by us will be assigned directly to your Facebook account.

(ee)Further information on the purpose and scope of data collection and use by Facebook can be found in the privacy statement provided below. You can also find additional information about your rights and privacy settings in this regards by contacting Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>; Further information about data collection: <http://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084>, <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other#applications> as well as <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info#everyoneinfo>. Facebook has also made itself subject to the EU-US-Privacy-Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.
